Guide to the North Star Mining Company and Associated Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Massachusetts Hill Mining Company, 1866-95; Series VI; 1.5
  Massachusetts Hill was taken over by North Star in 1894 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1888 Oct 11
        See: Oversize, Box 115, folder 2377
      - By-laws, 1888 Nov 5 (Box 24a, Folder 580)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meeting, 1889 May 8 (Box 24, Folder 581)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meeting, 1891 May 16 (Box 24, Folder 582)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meeting, 1893 May 10 (Box 24, Folder 583)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Indenture, promise to pay, 1866 Feb 6 (Box 24, Folder 584)
    - Stock documents
      - Certificates (blank), n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2128
      - Proxy, 1890 May 14 (Box 24, Folder 585)
      - Receipt for stock certificate tax, 1889 Apr 18 (Box 24, Folder 586)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Ore estimates, 1899 (Box 24, Folder 587)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Receipts, 1888-95 (Box 24, Folder 588-95)
- New York Hill Mining Company, 1871-95; Series VII; 5
  New York Hill was taken over by North Star in 1894 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1871 May 3 (Box 24, Folder 596)
      - By-laws, 1889 Jun 29 (Box 24b, Folder 597)
      - Application for dissolution and accompanying material, 1894 (Box 24, Folder 598)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1871-94 (Box 24c, Folder 599)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1871-77 (Box 24, Folder 600-04)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1885-94 (Box 24, Folder 605-15)
    - Correspondence
      - Received at San Francisco, 1885-90 (Box 24, Folder 616-21)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1892-94 (Box 24, Folder 622-24)
      - Sent by San Francisco, 1880-94 (Box 24, Folder 625)
      - Sent by Grass Valley, 1885-86 (Box 25, Folder 626-27)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Agreement, release and confirmation, 1879, 1881 (Box 25, Folder 628-29)
      - Indenture, assent, deed, 1886, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 630-31)
    - Stock documents
      - Ledger, 1875-89 (Box 25a, Folder 632)
      - Transfer journal, 1875-89 (Box 25b, Folder 633)
      - Assessment ledger, 1875-95 (Box 25c, Folder 634)
      - Statements of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 25, Folder 635)
      - List of stockholders, 1885-90
        See: Oversize, Box 98, folders 2227-32
      - List of stockholders, 1892, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 98, folders 2233-34
      - Proxy, 1890 Mar 25 (Box 25, Folder 636)
      - Certificate of increase of the capital stock, 1875 Jul 29 (Box 25, Folder 637)
      - Account of sale of stock for assessment and charges, 1885 Dec 28 (Box 25, Folder 638)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1889 (Box 25, Folder 639)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1891-92 (Box 25, Folder 640)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 641)
  - OPERATIONS RECORDS
    - Weekly reports, 1885-86 (Box 25, Folder 642-45)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Memoranda of bullion, 1885-86 (Box 25, Folder 646-47)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Ledger, 1871-89 (Box 25, Folder 648)
    - Cash book, 1871-89 (Box 25e, Folder 649)
    - Journal, 1871-89 (Box 25, Folder 650)
    - Statements of receipts and disbursements, 1885-86 (Box 25, Folder 651-52)
      See also: Oversize, Box 98, folders 2235-47
    - Statements of receipts and disbursements, 1889-93 (Box 25, Folder 653-56)
    - Paid vouchers, 1885-94 (Box 26, Folder 657-66)
      See also: Oversize, Box 98, folder 2248
    - Bank book (Swiss American Bank; F. Berton & Co.), 1875-85 (Box 26, Folder 667)
    - Bank book and checks (Alfred Borel & Co.), 1885-94 (Box 26, Folder 668-69)
    - Miscellaneous accounts, 1885, 1889 (Box 26, Folder 670)
  - PAY ROLL RECORDS
    - Pay roll records, 1885-86
      See: Statements of receipts and disbursements, folders 651-52
- North Star Mining Company, Series VIII; 53
  In 1929 North Star merged with the Empire becoming the Empire Star (Series II). Eventually North Star became part of the New Verde Mines which sold off the mines and equipment in 1958 (Series XI).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-laws, Minutes
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1899 Apr 7 (Box 27, Folder 671)
      - Certificate of incorporation, 1922 Apr 12 (Box 27, Folder 672)
      - By-laws, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 672A)
      - Minutes of trustees/stockholders meetings, 1867-87 (Box 27a, Folder 673)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1884-96 (Box 27b, Folder 674)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1896 (Box 27c, Folder 675)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1922-30 (Box 27, Folder 676)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1873 (Box 27, Folder 677)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1879-80 (Box 27, Folder 678-80)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1884-97 (Box 27, Folder 681-706)
        See also: Oversize, Box 99, folders 2249-53
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1898-99 (Box 28, Folder 707-12)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1904, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 713-14)
        See also: Oversize, Box 99, folder 2254
    - Correspondence
      - New York to San Francisco, 1885-91 (Box 28, Folder 715-24)
      - New York to San Francisco, 1892-97 (Box 29, Folder 725-38)
      - New York to San Francisco, 1898-99 (Box 30, Folder 739-43)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1879, 1881 (Box 30, Folder 744-45)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1884-86 (Box 30, Folder 746-56)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1886-92 (Box 31, Folder 757-70)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1893-98 (Box 32, Folder 771-82)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1899 (Box 33, Folder 783-85)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1904-05 (Box 33, Folder 786)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1908 (Box 33, Folder 787)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1915-17, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 788-90)
      - Sent by San Francisco, 1867-81 (Box 33a-33c, Folder 791-93)
      - Sent by San Francisco, 1884-99 (Box 33d-33f, Folder 794-96)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1886-91 (Box 34, Folder 797-808)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1892-95 (Box 35, Folder 809-21)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1896 (Box 36, Folder 822-33)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1897-98 (Box 37, Folder 834-46)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1898-99 (Box 38, Folder 847-59)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1899-1901 (Box 39, Folder 860-74)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1902-05 (Box 40, Folder 875-91)
        See also: Oversize, Box 115, folder 2378
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1905-08 (Box 41, Folder 892-907)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1908-09 (Box 42, Folder 908-22)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1911-13 (Box 42, Folder 923)
        See also: Oversize, Box 99, folder 2255
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1916, 1918 (Box 42, Folder 924)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1920-21 (Box 42, Folder 925)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1925, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 926)
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 927)
      - Sent by Grass Valley, 1884-1900 (Box 43a-43d, Folder 928-31)
        See also: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2129
      - Sent by Grass Valley, 1904-07 (Box 43e-43g, Folder 932-34)
    - Insurance
      - Policies, 1884-85
        See: Oversize, Box 99, folders 2256-57
      - Policies, 1887-99
        See: Oversize, Boxes 99-103, folders 2258-96
      - Policies, 1915
        See: Oversize, Box 103, folders 2297
      - Book for recording policies, 1889 (Box 43, Folder 935)
    - Accident Documents
      - Monthly reports to California Industrial Accident Commission, Dept. of Safety, Mining Division, 1917-18 (Box 43, Folder 936-37)
      - Agreement, 1891-92 (Box 43, Folder 938)
      - Reports, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 939)
      - Coroner's inquisitions, 1904-05 (Box 43, Folder 940-41)
      - Coroner's inquisitions, 1930 (Box 43, Folder 942)
      - Trials before the California Industrial Accident Commission, 1923, 1927 (Box 43, Folder 943-44)
      - Trials before the California Industrial Accident Commission, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 945)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Agreements, indenture, 1861, 1868 (Box 43, Folder 946-47)
      - Agreements, offer to lease mining claims, 1873, 1878 (Box 43, Folder 948-49)
      - Agreement, power of attorney, 1887-88 (Box 43, Folder 950-51)
      - Agreements, assent of stockholders, indenture, land petition, 1894-99 (Box 43, 43h, Folder 952-57)
        Includes bound volume "Contracts with outside tributers," stored in box 43h, folder 954.
      - Agreement, 1901 (Box 43, Folder 958)
      - Agreements, indenture, specifications for pump, order by Board, 1903-06 (Box 43, Folder 959-62)
      - Agreements, agreements of license, 1909-10 (Box 43, Folder 963-64)
      - Agreements, agreements of license, indenture, location notices, land petitions, 1913-19 (Box 43, Folder 965-71)
      - Agreement, indenture, 1921 (Box 43, Folder 972)
      - Agreements, contracts, leases, 1925-28 (Box 43, Folder 973-76)
      - List of title papers sent to New York (Box 43, Folder 977)
    - Court actions
      - North Star vs. Central Pacific Ry. Co. (U.S. Land Office), 1891, 1914 (Box 44, Folder 978)
      - Carson City Gold & Silver Mining Company vs. North Star (9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals), 1897 Oct 18 (Box 44, Folder 979)
      - In the matter of application by North Star for exclusion of lands from Nevada Irrigation District (Before Board of NID), 1924 (Box 44, Folder 980-82)
      - Nevada Irrigation District vs. North Star et al (California Superior Court), 1926 Sep 20 (Box 44, Folder 983)
    - Special Reports and Projects
      - Lodestar Quartz Mine, 1888, 1892 (Box 44, Folder 984)
      - [Shanghai] Consolidated Quartz Mine, 1889 Oct 30 (Box 44, Folder 985)
      - Walworth Mine, 1890-94 (Box 44, Folder 986)
      - Reilly, Wright property (Oro Flat Mine), 1891-95 (Box 44, Folder 987)
        See also: Oversize, Box 104, folder 2298
      - Massachusetts Hill properties, 1893-95 (Box 44, Folder 988)
        See also: Oversize, Box 104, folder 2299
      - Watt & Company mining claim, 1893-95 (Box 44, Folder 989)
      - Great Britain Quartz Mine, 1894 (Box 44, Folder 990)
      - Star Placer Mine, 1894 Feb 20 (Box 44, Folder 991)
      - Sinking pump, 1895 (Box 44, Folder 992)
      - Southern Quartz Mine, 1895 (Box 44, Folder 993)
      - Dipper Quartz Mine, 1896 Dec 29 (Box 44, Folder 994)
      - North Star power plant, 1898, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 994A-B)
      - Mount Pleasant mine inventory of machinery, 1900 Feb (Box 44, Folder 995)
      - Hoisting engine, 1900 (Box 44, Folder 996)
        See also: Oversize, Box 104, folder 2300
      - Strike and Root Lode claims, 1901 (Box 44, Folder 997)
      - Great Bear Quartz Mine, 1904-05 (Box 44, Folder 998)
      - Report with appendix on examination of certain mining properties in the vicinity of Grass Valley by Louis Janin, 1908 (Box 44, Folder 999)
      - Report on the Geology of the North Star Mine by Ernest Howe, 1910 Mar (Box 44, Folder 1000)
      - Champion Mines
        - Report on the geology of the Champion Mines by Ernest Howe, 1911 Feb-Mar (Box 44, Folder 1001)
        - Report on development, 1911, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1002-03)
        - [Champion Mines, Report of J. B. Stapler], 1918 Feb 15 (Box 44, Folder 1004)
      - [Report on the Golden Gate Mines by Fred M. Miller], 1912 Aug 15 (Box 44, Folder 1005)
      - New Ophir Mine and Daisy Hill Mine, 1916 (Box 44, Folder 1006)
      - Operative's report on activity in Central Shaft and at mine worker's Protective League meetings, 1919 Oct (Box 44, Folder 1007)
    - Stock documents
      See also "Copies of minutes and material from meetings" (Boxes 27-28, folders 677-713) for lists of stockholders and proxies
      - Ledger, 1867-84 (Box 45a, Folder 1008)
      - Subscriptions, ca. 1867 (Box 45, Folder 1009)
      - Receipts of stock sold, 1884 (Box 45, Folder 1010-11)
      - Transfer slips, 1888-95 (Box 45, Folder 1012-19)
      - Transfer slips, 1896-99 (Box 46, Folder 1020-23)
      - Assessment ledger, 1869-85 (Box 46a, Folder 1024)
      - Statements of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 46, Folder 1025)
      - Register of stockholders, 1887-99 (Box 46b, Folder 1026)
      - Names and addresses of stockholders, ca. 1888 (Box 46c, Folder 1027)
      - Lists of stockholders, 1885 Sep (Box 46, Folder 1028)
      - Lists of stockholders, 1888 Jan (Box 46, Folder 1029)
      - Lists of stockholders, 1895-96 (Box 46, Folder 1030)
        See also: Oversize, Box 104, folder 2301
      - Certificates (blank), ca. 1860, 1880 (Box 46, Folder 1030A)
      - Sale of delinquent stock, 1879, 1885 (Box 46, Folder 1031)
        See also: Oversize, Box 104, folder 2302
      - Proxies, 1890 (Box 46, Folder 1032)
      - Stockholders' authorizations to buy mining properties, 1894 (Box 46, Folder 1033-34)
      - Printed letters to stockholders, 1897, 1899 (Box 46, Folder 1035)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-79 (Box 46, Folder 1036)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1881 (Box 46, Folder 1037)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1884-89 (Box 46, Folder 1038)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1891-94 (Box 46, Folder 1039)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1896 (Box 46, Folder 1040)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1886,'89,'98,n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1041)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Monthly reports, 1887 (Box 46, Folder 1042)
    - Weekly reports, 1884-1901 (Box 46, Folder 1043-69)
    - Monthly mining reports, 1888-90 Jun (Box 47, Folder 1070-99)
      See also: Oversize, Box 115, folders 2379-82
    - Monthly mining reports, 1890 Jul-93 (Box 48, Folder 1100-41)
      See also: Oversize, Box 115-16, folders 2382-85
    - Monthly mining reports, 1894-96 (Box 49, Folder 1142-77)
      See also: Oversize, Box 116, folders 2386-88
    - Monthly mining reports, 1897-98 (Box 50, Folder 1178-1201)
      See also: Oversize, Box 116-17, folders 2389-90
    - Monthly mining reports, 1899-1900 (Box 51, Folder 1202-25)
      See also: Oversize, Box 117, folders 2391-92
    - Monthly mining reports, 1901 (Box 52, Folder 1226-37)
      See also: Oversize, Box 117, folders 2393
    - Daily reports, 1897, 1929 (Box 52a-52b, Folder 1238-39)
    - Tribute statements, 1891-96 (Box 53, Folder 1240)
    - Monthly North Star Mill records, 1898-1901 (Box 53a, Folder 1241)
    - Stockbridge Shaft reports, 1896-1900 (Box 53b-53c, Folder 1242-43)
    - Gold Hill reports, 1904 (Box 53, Folder 1243A)
    - North Star production, 1934, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1244)
    - Proposal for mine development, post-1894 (Box 53, Folder 1245)
    - Maps of North Star properties and mines, ca. 1914
      See: Oversize Box 119, folder 2398
    - Map of the Champion mines claims, n.d. (Box bsd, folder 1246)
    - Map of New York Hill mine, 1890 (Box bsd, folder 1247)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Amalgam, bullion, and sulphuret records
      Two sets of bound volumes; paper duplicates of sulphuret reports and amalgam, bullion reports
      - Bound volumes, set 1, 1884-96 (Box 53d-53e, Folder 1248-49)
      - Bound volumes, set 2, 1884-96 (Box 53f-53g, Folder 1250-51)
      - Amalgam, bullion reports (paper records), 1889 (Box 53, Folder 1252)
      - Amalgam, bullion reports (paper records), 1891-92 (Box 53, Folder 1253-54)
      - Sulphuret reports (paper records), 1888-97 (Box 53, Folder 1255-64)
    - Biweekly amalgam, bullion, and sulphuret reports
      - Bound volume, 1887-91 (Box 54a, Folder 1265)
      - Paper records, 1887-91 (Box 54, Folder 1266-70)
    - Daily amalgam and bullion records, 1892-1904 (Box 54, 54c-54c, Folder 1271-73)
    - Bullion slips and assay certificates, 1887-98 (Box 54, Folder 1274-86)
    - Ore and waste records
      Paper documents duplicate bound volume
      - Bound volume, 1886-1903 (Box 54, Folder 1287)
      - Paper documents, 1886-96
        See: Oversize Box 104, folder 2303
    - Massachusetts Hill ore delivered to North Star mill reports, 1896
      See: Oversize Box 105, folder 2314
    - Champion assays, 1917-20
      See: Percipatate and bar assays, p. 50-79 of Box 90, folder 1938A.
    - Summary of ore records, 1889
      See: Oversize, Box 105, folder 2315
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Annual statements, 1888
      See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2130
    - Annual statements, 1890-97 (Box 55, Folder 1288-89)
      See also: Oversize, Box 94, folders 2131-36
    - Cash book, 1896 (Box 55a, Folder 1289A)
    - Journal, 1884-93 (Box 55b, Folder 1290)
    - Journal, 1896 May (Box 55c, Folder 1291)
    - Journal, 1899-1900 (Box 55, Folder 1291A)
    - Monthly statements, 1884-87 (Box 55, Folder 1292-94)
      For the years 1884-93, these documents duplicate information in the Journal (Box 55, folder 1290). Similar information for the years 1894-97 can be found in superintendent's statements and vouchers (Boxes 57-66, folders 1408-1502)
      See also: Oversize, Box 105, folders 2316-18
    - Monthly statements, 1893-99
      See: Oversize, Boxes 105-07, folders 2319-29
    - Tabulated statements
      - Summaries, 1888-97
        See: Oversize, Box 107, folders 2330-31
      - Tabulated statements of superintendent's monthly account, 1890-99, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 107, folders 2332-43
    - Analyzed statements
      - Summaries, 1890-91
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2399
      - Monthly analyzed statement of disbursements (multiple copies)
        - Bound volume, set 1, 1888-91 (Box 55e, Folder 1295)
        - Bound volume, set 2, 1888-91 (Box 55, Folder 1296)
        - Paper documents, 1888
          Related Materials
          See: Oversize, Box 108, folder 2344
        - Paper documents, 1891-99
          See: Oversize, Box 108-09, folders 2345-58
    - Monthly tribute statements
      See superintendent's statements and vouchers Boxes 57-66, folders 1408- 1502
    - Monthly tribute statements, 1897-1904
      See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2400; Boxes 112-13, folders 2359-66
    - Tribute and wood ledger
      - Wood accounts, p. 1-170, 1884-96 (Box 55g, Folder 1297)
      - Monthly tribute statements, p. 198-355, 1886-96 (Box 55g, Folder 1297)
      - Tribute accounts, p. 361-411, 1885-86 (Box 55g, Folder 1297)
    - Accounts current of New York transfer agency, 1888-97 (Box 55, Folder 1298-1306)
    - Accounts of crushings of tribute ore
      - Stockbridge, p. 19-34, 1896-1901 (Box 55h, Folder 1307)
      - New York Hill, p. 51-52, 1900-01 (Box 55h, Folder 1307)
      - Gold Hill Shaft, p. 150-55, 1903-04 (Box 55h, Folder 1307)
    - Massachusetts Hill purchase account, 1895 (Box 55, Folder 1308)
    - Homes purchase accounts, 1920-21 (Box 55, Folder 1309)
    - Miscellaneous accounts, 1895, ca. 1898 (Box 55, Folder 1310-11)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1867 (Box 55, Folder 1312)
      Some secretary's vouchers from San Francisco office included
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1878-84 (Box 55, Folder 1313-19)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1885-89 (Box 56, Folder 1320-66)
      Some secretary's vouchers from San Francisco office included in the early years
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1890-94 (Box 57, Folder 1367-1414)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1894 (Box 58, Folder 1415-30)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1895 (Box 59, Folder 1431-44)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1895 (Box 60, Folder 1445-54)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1896 (Box 61, Folder 1455-64)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1896 (Box 62, Folder 1465-74)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1896-97 (Box 63, Folder 1475-84)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1897 (Box 64, Folder 1485-92)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1897 (Box 65, Folder 1493-1500)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1897 (Box 66, Folder 1501-02)
    - Superintendent's statements and vouchers, 1899, 1928 (Box 66, Folder 1503-04)
    - Drafts and checks
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1884-85
        See: Letters received at San Francisco, Box 30, folders 746-56
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1885-86 (Box 66, Folder 1505-13)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1888 (Box 66, Folder 1514-22)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1888-89 (Box 67, Folder 1523-35)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1889-91 (Box 68, Folder 1536-50)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1891-92 (Box 69, Folder 1551-69)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1892-94 (Box 70, Folder 1570-86)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1894-95 (Box 71, Folder 1587-1604)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1895-97 (Box 72, Folder 1605-22)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1897-98 (Box 73, Folder 1622A-31)
      - List of superintendent's drafts, 1896-98 (Box 73a, Folder 1632)
      - Record of drafts, 1884-98 (Box 73b-73f, Folder 1633-37)
      - Paid drafts, 1887-97 (Box 73g-73h, Folder 1638-39)
      - Superintendent's draft stubs, 1897-98 (Box 73i, Folder 1640)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1884-85 (Box 73, Folder 1641-47)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1885-86 (Box 74, Folder 1648-61)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1886-92 (Box 75, Folder 1662-69)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1892-93 (Box 76, Folder 1670-76)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1893 (Box 77, Folder 1677-83)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1893-94 (Box 78, Folder 1684-89)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1894 (Box 79, Folder 1690-97)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1894-96 (Box 80, Folder 1698-1708)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1896-97 (Box 81, Folder 1709-18)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1897 (Box 82, Folder 1719-24)
      - Superintendent's drafts, 1898 (Box 83, Folder 1725)
      - Bank books, 1884-93 (Box 83, Folder 1726-27)
      - Check stubs, 1884-96 (Box 83a-83e, Folder 1728-32)
      - Checks, 1884-86 (Box 83, Folder 1733-51)
      - Checks, 1886-88 (Box 84, Folder 1752-77)
      - Checks, 1888-90 (Box 85, Folder 1778-1801)
      - Checks, 1890-92 (Box 86, Folder 1802-25)
      - Checks, 1892-94 (Box 87, Folder 1826-49)
      - Checks, 1894-95 (Box 88, Folder 1850-69)
      - Checks, 1896 (Box 89, Folder 1870-82)
  - PAY ROLL RECORDS
    - Pay roll records, 1894-97
      See: Superintendent's statements and vouchers, Boxes 57-66, folders 1408- 1502
    - Time books, 1884-93 (Box 89a-89d, Folder 1883-86)
    - Time books
      - North Star, 1897-1901 (Box 89e, Folder 1887)
      - Stockbridge development, 1897-1902 (Box 89f-89g, Folder 1888-89)
    - Payment of wages sheets, 1919-20 (Box 89, Folder 1890-95)
    - Payment of wages sheets, 1921, 1923 (Box 90, Folder 1896-97)
  - INVENTORY RECORDS
    - Ledger, 1887-88 (Box 90a, Folder 1898)
    - Gold Hill invoice of machinery, ca. 1904 (Box 90, Folder 1899)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1901 (Box 90, Folder 1900)
- Rocky Bar Gold Mining Company, Series IX; 3
  From 1856-58 the Rocky Bar mine was owned by the Mount Hope Company (Series XI) which was then taken over by A. Chavanne & Co (Series XI). Rocky Bar was eventually taken over by North Star during the period 1891-93 and information on the mine after that period can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Correspondence
      - Letters, 1877 (Box 90, Folder 1901)
      - Letters, 1891-92 (Box 90, Folder 1902)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds